KEVIN GREER

DATA ANALYST

615-948-0633

kmgreer405@hotmail.com

🎗 🛮 Ann Arbor, MI

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kevinmgreer/

https://github.com/kmgreer405

ABOUT ME

I discovered my love for data analysis in early 2022, during the first of what would turn out to be many jump start courses. Since then, I have developed my skills in data analysis significantly, and would love to combine them with my background on and lifelong love of sports. To any workplace I will bring a passion for problem-solving and experience with various programming platforms and methods for data analysis.

SKILLS

Microsoft Office Github Python

Excel Tableau Jupyter

SQL PowerBI Pandas

Statistics Python

DATA ANALYSIS EXPERIENCE

Data Analysis Apprentice

Ian 2023 - Present

Nashville Software School, Nashville, TN
Intense part-time analysis boot camp exploring multiple
methods of manipulating, interpreting, and visualizing
data to solve real world problems.

- Transformed data into concise tables for analysis (Excel)
- Analyzed data to solve complex problems (Excel, SQL)
- Interpreted and visualized data frames (Excel)
- Created interactive dashboards (PowerBI, Tableau)
- Cleaned and filtered data to create Seaborn plots (Pandas)

Data Analytics Jumpstart

August 2022

Nashville Software School

Part-time boot camp exploring the basics of data analytics using real world data to complete a project for the Nashville City council.

- Achieved proficiency in SQL and Python
- Collaborated with community stakeholders
- Assembled unique visualizations in matplotlab and seaborn
- Communicated findings clearly and thoroughly using Folium

PROJECTS

Basketball Stats

Used Excel to cut down and manipulate NBA data (2015-2020) to create an interactive dashboard in Power BI where stakeholders could explore statistics of the league's top players.

App Trader

Made investment recommendations to an App Trader by creating a calculation in SQL that sifted through data cleaned in Excel to identify the most profitable apps in the previous year.

Nashville Predators Dashboard

Created a visual using Tableau that explored Nashville Predators draft picks year to year to the the top players drafted in the same year to understand how their picks have measured up and which teams seem to have the best talent scouts.

Lahman Baseball Statistics

Imported the Lahman baseball statistics database into SQL. Stretched my SQL skills performing queries to answer in-depth questions and display my end tables in an easy to read and easy to follow format.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Target Aug 2015-Present

- Directed the maintenance of a section of the store
- Monitored sales of a particular section and arranged for the restock of popular items
- Coordinated efficient unloading and organizing of merchandise
- Performed closing responsibilities in collaboration with other team members
- Answered guests' questions and addressed problems and complaints in person and via phone
- Handled transactions at the register and administered spectacular guest service
- Balanced needs of multiple guests simultaneously in a fast-paced retail environment

Nissan of Cookeville Jan 2015-Jul 2015

- Contributed to detailed log of each car worked on and its condition to invoice for service.
- Detailed recently sold, rental, and customer cars
- Provided transportation to customers

Kroger *May 2014-Jul 2014*

- Managed beverage stand inside the store
- Took responsibility for cleaning and maintaining the machines
- Completed inventory and placed orders for additional materials when needed
- Interacted with suppliers regularly

Ice Hockey Referee

Jan 2010 - Apr 2010

- Memorized and communicated Ice Hockey Rules and Regulations
- Maintained composure in high stress situations
- Kept detailed record of wins and losses

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School

Nashville, TN

Data Analyst Apprenticeship Jan 2023 - Present

Data Analytics Jumpstart Aug 2022

Web Development Jumpstart Feb 2022

Tennessee Technological University

2013 - 2015

Cookeville, TN

Completed 40 credits towards a BS in Civil Engineering